the ICICI Prudential Life Insurance
Company Limited FY2026 earnings
conference call.
As a reminder, all participant lines
will be in the listen-only mode, and
there will be an opportunity for you to
ask questions after the presentation
concludes.
Should you need assistance during the
conference call, please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
your touch-tone phone.
I now hand the conference over to Mr.
Anup Bagchi, MD and CEO of ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance Company
Limited. Thank you, and over to you,
sir.
Thank you.
Good afternoon, and welcome to the
results call of ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance Company
for the year ended March 31st, 2026.
I have several of my senior colleagues
with me on this call. Amit Palta, Chief
Product and Distribution Officer,
Girish Salian, CFO,
Jeet, Chief Service Delivery,
Manish, Chief Investment Officer, Souvik
Appointed Actuary, and Dheeraj, Chief
Investor Relations Officer. We're also
joined today by Amish Banker.
Amish started his career in branch
operations and has a deep understanding
of the customer life cycle, and
organization processes and systems.
He's currently the Chief Operations
Officer, and would be taking over will
be taking over as Chief Distribution
Officer from Amit Palta. Amit, as you
would have noted in the exchange update,
is moving on from the company having
spent more than two decades in the ICICI
Group. We wish him all the very best for
his future endeavors.
Let me start with some key updates. On
the regulatory front, we welcome the
idea's transition to India's
which will align our financial reporting
with global standards. This shift
enhances transparency and market
comparability, ensuring that our
financial statements reflect an improved
picture of value accretion.
On the economic front, in FY2026,
the Indian economy displayed resilience
while navigating external turbulence,
This stability was anchored by direct
tax
GST reforms, and RBI's supportive
monetary policy stance aimed at
stimulating the domestic consumption.
As a company, we also exhibited agility
and resilience, achieving a VNB of 26.29
billion, with VNB growth of 10.9% in
FY2026,
and worked to deliver long-term value to
our shareholders. Our VNB margin stood
at 24.7%
as compared to 22.8%
in FY2025.
Tax grew strongly by 34.6% year-on-year
to 16 billion.
Life insurance products, particularly
the retail protection segment, received
a significant boost, partly aided by the
GST reforms effective September 2025.
The retail sum assured growth for the
industry were higher by 2.5 times in the
post-reform figures
as compared to the pre-reform figure.
In the current year, our retail new
business sum assured reached 4.5
trillion, led by 50.9%
year-on-year growth in retail protection
in H2
2026, demonstrating our dominant
position in this segment.
In the savings category, despite the
external volatility of FY2026,
our AP remained steady and similar to
the previous year.
New business premium registered a
year-on-year growth of approximately 10%
to 248.10 billion in FY2026.
Our business growth has also been
delivered on a foundation of risk and
prudence, and is exhibited in our
resilient balance sheet.
In FY2026, we maintained an
industry-leading claim settlement ratio
of 99.3%
with an average turnaround time of 1.1
days.
Our early claims ratio stood at 22%,
best in class in the industry,
highlighting our focus on quality
business flows through the years.
Our 13-month persistency stood at 84.5%.
Our solvency ratio stood at 227.3%,
well capitalized and much ahead of the
regulatory requirement of 150%.
We continue to maintain our track record
of not having a single non-performing
asset in our investment portfolio since
inception of our company.
We remain committed to delivering
delivering superior value to our
customers by leveraging economies of
scale,
and aligning our cost structure closely
with our evolving product mix.
Notably, technology and digital
solutions have enabled us to increase
efficiency, resulting in a reduction of
40 basis points to 12.1%
in our savings
cost-to-premium ratio during FY2026.
Our AUM stood at 3.14 trillion, and our
total in-force sum assured grew by 16.9%
year-on-year to 46.11 trillion
at March 31st, 2026.
In the same year, our embedded value
grew by 10.5% year-on-year to reach
529.89
billion.
To summarize this year, as we celebrate
25 years of its service to our
customers, we would like to reaffirm our
commitment to deliver sustainable VNB
growth by balancing business growth,
profitability, and risk and prudence.
Towards this, we believe all the
necessary levers continue to be
available with us.
Thank you, and I'll now hand it over to
Amit to take you through the business
updates.
>> [clears throat]
>> Thank you, Anup.
Uh good afternoon, everyone.
As Anup mentioned, the past year was
defined by changing macroeconomic
landscape, shaped by both global and
domestic shifts, and additionally, we
also had a relatively high base of last
year, particularly in H1.
Quarter three onwards, the growth
momentum returned with retail AP growth
of 10% year-on-year.
This positive trajectory sustained
throughout quarter four until renewed
geopolitical disruptions emerged in
March 2026.
Despite these disruptions, we managed to
deliver growth in quarter four,
with AP registering 9.54%
year-on-year growth.
On a full year basis, AP grew by 2.2%
year-on-year to 106.41 billion.
Coming to product-wise performance,
our core focus area, retail protection,
grew by 60.5%
year-on-year in quarter four,
uh resulting in a full year growth of
32.3%
with an estimated 13% of the addressable
population currently being covered
through retail protection.
We believe this segment offers a
multi-decadal growth opportunity.
>> [clears throat]
>> Group protection, which includes credit
life and group term business, grew by
7.1% year-on-year in FY26. Within that,
group term business grew by 14.6%
year-on-year, and credit life business
grew by 1.8% year-on-year.
MFI segment, which witnessed challenges
at start of the year, has seen recovery
from quarter three onwards.
Linked business AP grew by 1.6%
year-on-year in FY26, impacted by
volatile equity markets.
Two-year CAGR for linked business AP
stood at 14.2%.
We continue to focus on increasing the
contribution from high sum assured units
in this segment.
Such products are less impacted by
market volatility, thereby providing
stability to linked category to a large
extent.
The non-linked savings AP grew at 15.4%
year-on-year for the first nine months.
Last year in quarter four, we launched a
new product in this segment, which had a
very good response.
This year quarter four, as business from
that product normalized, non-linked
business has declined year-on-year in
quarter four.
On full year basis, the business and
contribution from non-linked savings
business is at similar level last year.
Annuity business four-year CAGR stood at
approximately 20%. This business has
stabilized at around 7% of our retail
mix.
Group funds business grew by 26%
year-on-year.
Now, let me talk about channel-wise
performance.
Agency channel AP stood at 26.86
billion, and direct channel AP stood at
14.30 billion in FY2026.
Together, these channels contributed
47.4%
to overall retail AP.
These channels have declined this year,
primarily due to the high base of linked
and annuity businesses in the previous
year.
In the agency channel, growth trajectory
has shown consistent sequential
improvement throughout this year.
As a strategic priority, we have been
investing in the channel from a
long-term perspective. Our roadmap
centers on micro-market led branch
strategy, and using technology and
analytics as a productivity lever.
By equipping agents with tools and
analytics to automate administrative
tasks, they can pivot their focus
towards high value generating
activities.
In the direct channel, focus will be to
deepen NRI segment through gift city,
and scale up online channel through
differentiated offerings.
Bancassurance channel grew by 3.6%
year-on-year, and contributed 29.8% to
total AP.
Partnership distribution channel grew by
23.4% year-on-year, and contributed
13.2%
to AP mix in FY26.
In bancassurance distribution channel,
our focus continues to be on adding new
partnerships, and improving the share of
shop in each partnership.
Group business grew by 14.5%
year-on-year, and contributed 18.3% to
the overall AP mix in FY2026.
Today, we have the strength of 2.42
lakhs advisors, 53 bank partnerships
with access to more than 26,400 bank
branches, and 1,500 plus non-bank
partnerships.
To summarize, our primary focus will be
to drive business growth through a micro
market strategy in proprietary channels.
By deepening our distribution, we shall
gain access to a wider range of customer
profiles which enhances our ability to
seamlessly shift between product
segments as per macro environment.
We believe this will help us keep our
product and channel mix balanced and
deliver sustainable growth irrespective
of the market environment over the long
term.
I would now hand it over to Dhiren to
talk you through the financial update.
Thank you, Amit. Good afternoon,
everyone.
Let me start with some
efficiency-related aspects.
As you're aware, we have undertaken
various cost optimization initiatives in
the past 2 years
to make our cost structure aligned to
our prevailing product mix.
One of them being the use of AIML, which
is being embedded across the entire
customer journey.
That is driving targeted demand
generation,
automated underwriting, improved renewal
retention, enhanced customer service,
and effective claims investigation.
Upsell programs and digital lead
conversion, both supported by machine
learning models, continue to contribute
to growth.
While advanced fraud detection and only
claims identification help mitigate risk
and improve profitability.
We have also deployed AI-led face
matching between KYC documents and
customer images to reduce fraud risk.
GenAI-based categorization of incoming
customer emails has significantly
improved turnaround times.
And AI-driven medical summarization is
enabling faster and more efficient
underwriting decisions.
Further details on usage of AIML across
our processes is shown on slide number
36 of the presentation.
As can be seen on slide 12, the various
productivity enhancements have helped in
reducing cost to premium ratios for our
savings line of business by 40 basis
points to 12.1% in FY2026.
This cost reduction is after accounting
for unavailability of input tax credit,
which is effective September 22nd, 2025.
Our total cost to premium ratios for
FY2026 stood at 18.2%
and remained stable at previous year's
levels.
The company's profit after tax grew by
34.6% year-on-year to rupees 16 billion
in FY2026.
Primarily driven by higher investment
income from shareholder funds.
This includes a gain of rupees 1.14
billion realized from sale of 100%
equity shareholding in ICICI Pension
Fund Management Company, which was
erstwhile called ICICI Prudential
Pension Funds Management Company
Limited.
Excluding this sale transaction, PAT
grew by 25% year-on-year in FY2026.
Our solvency ratio continues to be
strong at 227.3%.
The improvement in solvency is primarily
due to increase in profit after tax and
realization from sale of subsidiary.
Our assets under management stood at
rupees 3. 13 trillion as of March 31st,
2026.
Value of new business, VNB, grew by
10.9% year-on-year to rupees 26.29
billion.
As you're aware, our focus is on growing
the absolute VNB, which we have been
able to achieve through improvement in
product mix and operational
efficiencies, even after accounting for
the unavailability of input tax credit.
VNB margin expanded by 190 basis points
year-on-year to 24.7%
in the current year.
Margin expansion has been led by
improvements in new business profile and
economic assumption changes.
Protection mix for the year has
increased by 2.2% year-on-year to 17.9%.
Additionally, we have also been working
towards improving the profitability of
each line of business through longer
tenure policies, higher sum assured
multiples, and increasing rider
attachment.
The policy term on the savings line of
business has increased from 26 years in
FY2025
to 29 years in FY2026.
Retail sum assured has grown by 35%
year-on-year in the current year.
The expansion was offset by operating
assumption changes, which is primarily
due to unavailability of input tax
credit on individual businesses,
and some updates to persistency.
As shown in slide 16, our embedded value
grew by 10.5% year-on-year
to rupees 529.89
billion at March 31st, 2026.
Our embedded value operating profit
stood at rupees 57.02 billion in FY2026.
The breakup of the EVOP is as follows.
Unwind contribution for FY2026 is 7.4%
of the opening EV.
VNB of 26.29 billion rupees is 5.5% of
the opening EV.
Unwind and VNB together constitutes
12.9% of the opening EV.
Operating assumption change is 0.5% of
the opening EV,
negative, and primarily on account of
unavailability of input tax credit and
some updates to persistency as I'd
mentioned earlier.
Both mortality and experience expense
variance are positive for the year and
broadly in line with our expectations.
Persistency variance is a negative 2.64
billion rupees, which is largely on
account of the 100% premium back annuity
product where the persistency experience
fell short of long-term assumption.
As you're aware, it was an
industry-first product and coincided
with regulatory discussions aimed at
including increasing surrender values
for traditional savings products.
During the year, given the market
volatility and tight liquidity scenarios
where market returns were negative, we
believe that customers used the amount
for withdrawals in times of need.
While we ensured that economic benefits
were safeguarded from our company's
perspective, the future earnings, which
is part of EV, was impacted due to these
withdrawals.
Consequently, the ROEV for financial
year 2026 stands at 11.9%.
The total economic and investment
variance is um negative 7.78 billion
rupees due to a shift in the yield curve
and equity market movements.
Our VNB and EV have been reviewed
independently by Milliman Advisors LLP,
and their opinion is available in the
results pack submitted to the exchanges.
Further sensitivity details are
available on slide 17.
This concludes the financial
performance.
I will now hand it over to Judhajit to
talk you through the ESG updates.
Thank you, Dhiren.
I I will be sharing the salient aspects
of our ESG journey.
We continue to retain the highest
ranking in the Indian life insurance
industry
as per leading global and Indian ESG
rating agencies.
We're also delighted to share
that during Q4 2026, we received the
platinum award for our ESG report
for 2025 at the Vision Awards organized
by the League of American Communications
Professionals.
We were also recognized among India's
top
60 most sustainable companies by
Business World.
I will now share the key highlights
under each of the ESG focus areas.
Environment,
we continue to look at ways and means of
reducing our carbon footprint by
adopting green energy across various
branches in across India.
Apart from the LEED platinum
certificate, which is a green building
rating for the company's our
headquarters here,
we have also got the IGBC platinum green
building certification for four other
branches.
Under responsible investing, we are a
signatory to the UN Principles for
Responsible Investment.
We have completed our third annual
reporting on responsible investing
activities, and we shall continue to
remain committed to promote ESG factors
in our investment decisions.
Um on the diversity front, our gender
diversity is now at 30%, and we shall
continue to strive to improve it from
here.
Uh as far as community is concerned,
our goal has been to increase financial
inclusion through specially designed
microinsurance products targeting
socially and economically weaker
sections, and we have covered 53.8
million lives as of March 31st, 2026.
This year, we settled more than 3 lakh
retail and group claims with an overall
claim settlement ratio of 99.8%.
On the CSR front, through ICICI
Foundation, we have established killing
labs at four locations to facilitate
advanced industrial and skill training.
While in the area of healthcare, we
supported the Indian Cancer Society to
conduct surgeries
for almost more than 90 patients.
Governance,
our board has a majority of independent
directors, enabling the separation of
the board's supervisory role from
executive management.
I would like to reaffirm our commitment
again
to create a culture that embraces
sustainability and goes beyond goals and
targets.
Thank you very much. We're now happy to
take any questions that you may have.
Thank you very much.
We will now begin the question and
answer session.
Anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their touch-tone
telephone.
If you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue, you may press star and
two.
Participants are requested to use their
headsets while asking a question.
Ladies and gentlemen, we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles.
We'll take our first question from the
line of Swarnabha Mukherjee from BNP
Securities. Please go ahead.
Hi, sir. Good afternoon,
and congratulations with set of numbers.
Um so, I have three questions. First of
all, just wanted to understand in terms
of growth, how should we think about um
in the upcoming year, given that
you know, uh this particular year, how
the growth has
uh trended, I mean, gives us a very
favorable base to grow. Uh so, if I if
you could outline your strategy of how
you are thinking about FY27,
and
given that, you know, last year, you
know, there was this launch of par
product, uh and you highlighted that
which could have led to a slower growth
in the non-linked channel. Uh but, uh,
know, what are your thoughts on the
non-par category? How do you see it? And
parallelly also, if you could provide us
the mix of par non-par for the quarter.
Uh, that's one. And, then sir, on the
VNB, uh, margin side, if you could
highlight, you know, have, uh, you know,
all the persistency rate changes that
you are seeing, uh, you're you're
experiencing, has that been, uh, taken
into the assumptions or can something
incremental come or if you're observing
anything due to the surrender value
regulation that you might want to
highlight? And in that case, then, uh,
you know, how should we think about the
VNB margin, uh, numbers? Should we take
the current year numbers more of a
baseline, uh, if kind of the product mix
sustains?
Uh, so this is, uh, yeah, I think so.
This is broadly, uh, my queries, if you
could answer. Thanks.
Hi Supratim, this is Dhiren here. Uh, so
let me pick up, uh, some of your
questions. Uh, in terms of growth for
the, uh, next financial year, I think
this is quite a volatile time at this
stage. Uh, and I'm sure you would have
seen the way the markets have behaved
over the last month of the financial
year. Uh, I think this is still going to
be a bit of a wait-and-watch. Uh, you're
right. Specifically for us, we do have a
base that is, uh, good for us, but
again, it will depend upon how things
shape up, uh, in the environment.
Uh, so it's a little early for us to
commit as to what the number should look
like for the rest of the year, but rest
assured, I think the way that we're
approaching the problem is that we will
continue to go granular, continue to
understand who are these customer
segments that we should be looking at,
what are the product fits that we would
need, work with our distribution
channels to be able to deliver the right
proposition for customers as well as
shareholders. That, uh, objective and
that, uh, process continues. Uh, there's
no unwavering on that front.
Coming to your second question in terms
of, uh, what is the split between, uh,
par and non-par for the year, it's
roughly, uh, 2:1 ratio. Uh, it's been
broadly in that range. Some quarters a
little higher, some quarters a little
lower, uh, but broadly in the 2:1 range,
uh, for the year.
Uh, coming to your question, third
question, which is on, uh, the
persistency experience. See, our,
process around, uh, looking at
assumptions and experiences is to look
at what is temporary and what is
permanent. So, and we do this at every
year, uh, towards the end of the year in
terms of how these assumptions are
shaping up. So, whatever is known at
this point, uh, we will incorporate as
part of our,
uh, assumption setting. Uh, if there are
experiences that we see are temporary in
nature, uh, or they pertain to
quarantined portfolios, they'll allow
that to go through, uh, the variance.
Uh, so at this point, we have factored
what we know on terms of persistency, in
terms of mortality, and in terms of
expenses as part of our, uh, margin. So,
this essentially becomes the baseline
for us going forward.
All right, very helpful, Dhiren. Just,
uh, couple of follow-ups on, uh, you
know, two aspects. One is on the growth,
as you mentioned, I understand that this
is a volatile year, but like if I were
to look at from the channel side also, I
mean, this year's, uh, growth has been
primarily heavily lifted by your
partnerships. So, uh, I mean, what would
be, uh, you know, what,
uh, how should we think about, say, the
other channels? For example, agency this
year has been, uh, tepid. So, how, uh,
how do you plan to activate, uh, or go
about, uh, driving that channel? I
understand that banca, uh, given, uh,
you know, the base of, uh, ICICI Bank,
uh, there may might be a steadiness in
that number, but particularly on the
agency, I wanted to query. And also,
like on the on the persistency part, in
surrender value related regulations, are
you seeing any delta, uh, apart from the
annuity product? That's what I wanted to
understand.
Thanks.
Yeah, so on the, uh, early experience of
surrender value, uh, products, I am
we're not seeing anything too different.
Uh, but it's a little too early to call,
because we only got about 5 to 6 months
of experience, and we have allowed the
whole year to pan out for that.
Yeah, in terms of growth, you're right,
agency has has not had a great year. In
that sense, the growth has not been, uh,
great. So, that extent, it does form a,
uh, a
fairly uh, good base for us into the
coming year. But like I mentioned, we'll
continue to work at it granularly,
understand what are these micro segments
that we need to go after, and, uh, work
with that.
All right, thank you. Thanks, Dhiren.
Uh, all the best for FY24.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Supratim Datta from Jefferies.
Please go ahead.
Um, I thanks a lot for the opportunity.
Uh, I have three questions, you know,
starting with the growth aspect. Could
you help us understand how customer
behavior has changed with respect to
products post the start of this Middle
East war? Are you seeing any increase in
demand for non-par policies in this
current environment?
And, you know, how are you seeing the
demand of ULIPs, um, in mid-March and
early April? If you could give us some
color around the trends, that would be
helpful. Because what I see is in March,
despite the lower base, the agency
channel has declined. Uh, and this
channel should ideally have lower ULIP
exposure. So, you know,
trying to understand what's happening
there. Uh, on the margin bit, uh, what I
wanted to understand is despite the rise
in group funds in fourth quarter, uh,
ICICI has witnessed a sequential rise in
margins. Uh, is this a function of
higher earnings in some of the non-par
products and, you know, potentially, uh,
protection as well, or is there some
other driver here um, that we should
look at? And lastly, coming to the Ind
AS transition. Now, with Ind AS rolling
out from 1st of April, wanted to
understand, would you be sharing the Ind
AS accounts from next quarter? And how
would, uh, this compare with the CSM in
force? If you could give us some color
and, you know, how does this change your
capital position as well? Um, you know,
if you could give us some color on that,
that also would be very helpful. Thank
you.
Hi Supratim. Uh, let me cover Ind AS
first. Uh, so yes, uh, technically we
are live, we should be live with Ind AS.
Uh, but as approved by the board, we
will be seeking board variance for a
year. Uh, one of the most fundamental
points are that, uh, some of the, uh,
the decisions around how the, uh, inputs
could be provided for computing uh, the
CSM, I think we still await some clarity
from the joint expert group. Uh, the
other thing also is that, uh, this is
too short a time for us to transition
into Ind AS given the fact that we are
uh, typically, uh, live with our results
by the first 15 days of the, uh,
quarter. Uh, so we would need some time
to be able to gear our systems up to be
able to manage the transition there.
Uh, in in terms of, uh, the capital
position, uh, I believe the regulator
still wants us to use the erstwhile
solvency, uh, formulas. So, until we
wait to see how the, uh, RBC gets
implemented, uh, we would continue with
our current solvency basis, on which
we're quite strong at, uh, 220%.
Uh, coming to your second question that
you had asked, which is on margin, uh,
the margin support has largely come in
by the growth in protection that you can
see for the current quarter, which has
been quite strong. Uh, in addition to,
of course, all the improvements to
profitability that we've been doing
across all other savings lines of
business,
as I mentioned earlier.
Uh, your first question was on what are
the upcoming trends? Uh, little too
early to call, uh, Supratim, till we get
it, uh, settled. I do believe that the
the war in, uh, West Asia has to some
extent impacted new business sales in
the month of,
uh, March. Uh, difficult to guess how
much it would be, but, uh, clearly there
has been some impact.
Um, thanks a lot, Dhiren, for this
color. So, just wanted to understand,
has things been more on ULIP or has it
been across-the-board, uh, slowdown in
demand in mid-March?
Uh, it's been across-the-board, except
for protection. Okay.
Got it. Understood. Thank you.
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Shreya
Shivani from Nomura. Please go ahead.
Yeah, hi. Uh, good afternoon. Thank you
for the opportunity and, uh,
congratulations on a,
uh, good set of, uh, numbers. Uh, I have
two questions, um,
both on the EV walk. Uh, first is, uh,
the operating assumption changes that
we've taken, is it only the, uh,
persistency operating assumption or
there are certain changes you've done
with assumptions in mortality or
expense, et cetera? And second is, I
mean, it's the ROEVs, it's at 11.9. Now,
uh, I mean, even if I had assumed a zero
value for operating assumption changes
and a zero for, uh, persistency variance
instead of negative number, I would
still be at a 12.9 or so. So, what is
genuinely our uh, steady state ROEVs
that we should assume, um, because we
are
we are already under the cost of equity
in FY24. How should I think about it for
for for that matter? Yeah.
Hi Shreya. Uh, so coming to your
question on,
uh, operating assumption changes in EV,
as I mentioned on my opening remarks,
it's primarily on account of
unavailability of input tax credit and
then some updates to persistency.
Uh, this entire, if you recall, this
conversation had started in September as
to the impact of the, uh, unavailability
of, uh, input tax credit due to GST
reforms. That has been the bigger
component out of, uh, this operating
assumption change. Okay, right.
Right. Now, uh, coming to ROEV, uh, yes,
this, uh, without the assumption changes
and variance, we're at the 13% range.
Now, technically, on a longer-term
basis, we should still be at the 13 to
14% range, depending, of course, on how
the, uh, yield curve, uh, shapes up,
depending, of course on how they are
able to grow VNB and that becomes the
two primary drivers of how you determine
ROEV. But
from that sense that yes should be life
actually is life this year and uh
if you get the four bidders and we will
go live on that next year.
Looking at
returns on earnings will become much
easier when you look at the IND-AS
numbers.
The ROEV will have less significance
going forward.
Got it. Got it.
With IND-AS it does not impact the ROEV
whatsoever but probably will not be
looking at the ROEVs going ahead is what
your point of view is, right?
Yeah, my sense is most commentators and
analysts would end up looking at ROEs
because then that would
be at least comparable to how the rest
of the market is
outside of insurance.
Comparison becomes much easier then.
For want of any other metric we are in
this ROEV world at this point.
Right. And there is no impact whatsoever
of IFRS on the EV work, right?
Nothing from the even if
say a risk-based solvency comes through
nothing gets changed in in this matrix,
right?
No, risk-based solvency only determine
your capital position. Correct. Okay.
Nothing happens here.
Yeah, all right.
Okay.
So, there's no any questions. Thank you.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of
Jain from Motilal Oswal. Please go
ahead.
Yeah, hi.
Couple of questions. First on if I look
at the protection business the premium
growth exceeds the sum assured growth.
How should how should we read that?
Whether you know
it's you know more
you know
return of premium products that have
come in or the how how should we kind of
read that? That's one. And second is
more of a structural question on
embedded value variance. Fairly you know
in FY24 we had a mortality variance then
in FY25 we had a
assumption change and now we have a
persistency impact
both on variance as well as assumption
change.
You know this has been constantly
negative for us for the past three
fiscals.
How should we kind of think about this
going ahead and whether you know your
assumptions are
fairly easy now
to what extent that you know the
assumptions are more moderate or more
conservative
and you could start looking at more
positive variance or assumption changes
going right. Just just some color on
that so that would be helpful. Thanks.
So, Preeshit, right? When you look at
the protection sum assured growth that's
been at about 48%
sum assured on uh
So, the growth on retail protection has
been at higher at about 60%.
The retail new business sum assured
actually consists of both protection and
savings.
So, you will have to offset the two
together. So, the retail sum assured is
not purely protection because see by by
the fundamental construct of products in
India savings products in India you end
up providing 10x cover for most of our
products.
So, that itself forms a sum assured that
comes on board, right?
Coming to your question on embedded
value and how we look at how our
assumptions are being set. See, frankly
we run a very diversified portfolio.
And our approach to setting assumptions
is to understand whether these
potential differences between an
assumption that you have set and the
resulting experience that we see at this
point is that temporary or or permanent?
Now the way you always look at
the businesses that come in is you group
them into cohorts and as you look at
each cohort you are trying to identify
whether
cohorts look alike or do you need to
separate these cohorts? And again given
the underlying variability of the
underlying
diversity diversity of our business you
have to start looking at each of these
cohorts as they gain meaningful size.
As the separation you start to see
assumption changes. If I had a
homogeneous portfolio then ideally you
should not see any assumption changes at
all or even variances. But given the
diversity of the underlying business
that you bring you have to look at
cohorts and you have to then start
segregating cohorts as they start to
gain size and significance.
So, in any case as you look at the
overall experience and assumption
changes
these are marginal.
There have been points in time when we
had positive assumption changes as well.
But overall you see that the business is
being
ensured that the underlying assumption
that go in are reflective of what we see
today.
Got that. And now economic assumption
changes could you split that between
equity and debt?
It's largely debt.
Almost all of it.
Okay. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Madhukar Ladha from JP Morgan.
Please go ahead.
Hi, good afternoon. Thank you for taking
my question. First
you know
see in the beginning of last year we
were sort of targeting
about or at least at par with private
life insurance
you know retail AP growth.
I mean we've significantly sort of
underperformed that level.
Now going into sort of FY27 and onwards
what do you think should should you know
be your target and how do you think you
will achieve that target? Like if if you
can sort of quantify
you know any sort of meaningful changes
that that you are doing
that will you know lead us to believe
that
that we will be able to sort of you know
achieve higher retail retail AP sort of
growth, right? So, that's my first
question.
And and second
also if I look at persistency
we are seeing a decline for the 60th
first month, 13th month and and also I
think 25th month. So, what's happening
over there?
Third
with significant
I mean you know interest rates have gone
up, bond yields have sort of gone up.
That
should help our margins.
What
will enable us to sell more non-par or
or you know as as a company what's what
what
as a management how can you sell more
non-par would be my my question. Yeah,
these would be my three questions. And
also if you can split your economic
variance between debt and equity. Yeah.
Thanks.
Hi Madhukar, I just answered the
question on Preeshit.
The economic variance is largely debt.
Okay. In your first question where you
mentioned about growth
actually when you look at the two-year
CAGR we're still in the range of 7-8%.
Yes, it is not in line with the market
but then we've continued to see
work continue to work at at a granular
level to see what are those customer
segments that are available to us
through our distribution and where can
we generate growth from. So, we are not
divorced from the market. Very clearly
we're looking at
working at least at the market and then
look to work beyond that.
Largely when you look at the market the
two-year growth seems to be in the range
of 10 to 11%.
We are in the range of about 7 to 8%.
So, some work left but we're not too far
off.
You asked another question on to sort of
interrupt on on that but you know if you
look at the two-year CAGR then that may
be the case but
but if you come to more recent time then
last year's number FY26 would suggest
that
we are losing some more ground.
Right? So, so in that sense
there'd be more to catch up moving into
FY27 period.
So, Madhukar we've discussed this
earlier also. I think the focus for our
company is to be able to grow VNB in a
sustainable fashion.
I think the large component of VNB does
absolutely come from AP.
So, as you rightly pointed out yes, two
years slightly lower than market but
when I look at this year's numbers in
terms of AP at 2% growth VNB is at 11%
growth and you can see the consistency
in the margin that has held up all
through the year.
So, I think we're working at it
sustainably to work at it gradually to
see how we can deliver growth in a
sustainable format.
Your second question was on
persistency. 61st month we discussed
this earlier. This has been due to our
regulatory definition change.
25th month is a new phenomena. Yes, I
think some of the
spillover from the 13th month is coming
through to the 25th month at this point.
You had another question in terms of how
can we sustainably grow non-par?
I think one of the challenges that we
run up as an industry is that
our product does get compared to what
bank FD rates are
in the current environment when bank FD
rates continue to be fairly steep.
The product that we price product that
we offer does not look as attractive
because very clearly the way that we set
up our products is to price off the
G-sec. And so the return over the longer
term has to be priced off the G-sec.
Uh
There may be other considerations that
banks may be using to set up their
deposit rate.
But whenever there is a dichotomy
between the deposit rates and the
non-par IRR's, uh, then you will see
customers swing from one to another.
I hope that answers your question.
Yeah, that's that's helpful.
Uh, thanks a lot and all the best.
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Umang
Shah from Banyan Tree Advisors PMS.
Please go ahead.
Mr. Umang Shah, your line is unmuted.
Please go ahead with your question.
Hello. Am I audible?
Yes, please go ahead.
>> Yes, you are.
>> you for the opportunity. Yeah, thank you
for the opportunity. Uh, sir, one
question was,
till FY '24 we were giving VNB breakup
uh, among the various segments. Uh, if
you can give that number for FY '26 and
FY '25, that would be great.
Uh,
we align with the market on this front,
Umang.
Okay. Okay. Sure. Sure. That is very
good. I mean, that will be quite
helpful. Uh, but sure, I understand. Uh,
so second question was, the persistency
decline in 13th month cohort, um, has it
got Does it have a large part of annuity
product or it's across across segments?
A large part driven by annuity. Uh,
there are of course some segments that
you have seen some product channel
cohorts that have not performed on par.
Okay. Okay. And sir, when we have a
persistency which is worse than what you
were expecting, uh, does it benefit the
VNB or does it, uh, not benefit the VNB?
Umang, it doesn't benefit. Uh, so the
way we look at our assumption setting is
that we evaluate at the end of the year.
We take a view as to which of these are
permanent impairments in that sense.
Uh, for those we take an assumption
change. Uh, those that we believe are
temporary will allow that to run through
the variance.
Okay. Okay. Sure, sir. And sir, FY, uh,
so
you know, I think that's that's all. I
think I'm covered. I'll get back in the
queue. Thank you.
Thanks, Umang.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Vinod Rajamani from Nirmal Bang.
Please go ahead.
Yeah, thank you for taking my question.
So, I just saw most of my questions are
answered. I just had one question, uh,
what happens to the negotiations that
that were going on with
the distributors on commission and so
on?
Uh,
should we expect that,
uh, they are mostly done? And if so,
then, uh, you know, could we see agency
doing, uh,
uh,
all all channels, but especially agency
being
better, uh, in FY '27? That that was the
only question I had. Thank you.
Uh, so Vinod, the
negotiations and conversations with
distribution, be it agency or otherwise,
is always on.
Uh,
we we look to offer the remuneration
that is appropriate in line with the
product and the pricing that we have,
uh, built that is accretive to both
shareholders as well. So, at all points
in time, this is a continuous
conversation. There is never a start or
a stop to this. Uh, it will continue. It
has continued. It will continue and
will,
uh, keep going forward as well.
So, it is a continuous exercise as we
bring out new products and new
propositions, uh, we will continue to
work with our distribution to see how we
could deliver these products to the
relevant customer bases in a efficient
format.
Okay. So, uh, so no conclusion so far. I
mean, this was
it's
ongoing for some time. So,
there's been no, uh, what do you say?
There's been no agreement or something
reached.
How should we look at it?
Agreements have been reached, uh, with
all our distribution. We are where we
are and you are seeing the 24.7%
VNB margin.
Understood. Thanks so much. Yeah.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Sanket Goda from Avendus Spark.
Please go ahead.
Uh, thank you. I have few questions just
to start with. Uh, the uptick in the
margin in in the fourth quarter around
25.2,
uh, can we attribute predominantly to to
the favorable yield curve at least in
the month of March?
And and and and related to that, uh, in
in the VNB walk, uh, what we see as 250
basis point addition to the VNB margin,
uh, due to economic variance, is it
largely because of the yield curve
benefit which which which played in the
current year, uh, to to to bump up the
margin?
Sanket, when you look at the yield
curves and especially in in the
perspective of non
uh, non-par products and which also
includes protection,
uh, one has to look at what the pricing
is and what the yield curve is and what
is the expected margin that one wants
out of it.
So, as yield curves move, depending upon
your underlying costs, and of course you
know this year there has been an impact
of GST,
pricing has, uh, swung in that
direction. So, if we have got a benefit
of the yield curve, we would not have
changed We didn't change the pricing.
Uh, okay. Yield curve So, basically what
you are saying is that fashion.
Yeah, given what you are trying to say
that, uh, you did not, uh, change the
IRR of the end consumer or to the end
consumer despite the benefit and and
probably because of that thing the GST
impact to some extent got negated. It it
it's
Yeah, so if you look at the VNB walk,
right? What we have called out is the,
uh, movement across from 22.7 to 20.8 to
24.7. Now, here the product repricing,
whatever that we have done, is all
sitting as part of the new business
profile.
Right? And all the yield curve changes
are now part of the economic assumption
change. So, if I'm making any pricing
changes, it is a new product that have
come on board.
Understood. No, that's a different My my
point was that you got double benefit,
right? Your product mix also changed and
and on top of it you got an positive
economic variance number. But naturally,
GST impact of -3.9 will be there in the
VNB. So, just wanted to assume that the
product mix moved favorably and and also
you took the benefit of economic
variance to largely negate the impact
of, uh, other changes which might be
largely related to GST thing.
You take everything together, Sanket.
So, one We have been working very hard
at cost efficiencies across the years,
which I spoke of earlier. So, the
benefit of the cost efficiency is
something that we have taken on board as
you go down our pricing.
Because I'm getting cost efficiencies, I
can continue to hold the price as it is.
Now, this is seterus paribus.
My
>> [clears throat]
>> Some of my cost efficiency was negated
due to the GST impact. So, technically I
should have changed my pricing. But then
I also had the, uh, improving yield
curve, which allowed me to hold on to
prices at that point.
Actually, if you look at the entire
period, there have been very marginal
price changes that too in certain
cohorts, not across the board. And I
believe that answers answers the
question earlier as well.
One doesn't One did not expect on mass
price changes to happen and that has not
happened.
Uh,
okay. So, given the the reason I was
asking this question is that, given
given growth is becoming soft a bit now
and, uh, probably if yield curve becomes
much more steeper, which which was very
visible in the month of March, uh, is it
fair to say that to to fill in the
growth, you you will pass on some
benefit to the consumers and and and
maybe maybe that could play a role for
for the growth. And and related to that
point only is that, given given we
largely did only single premium annuity
in the current year, um, given given for
our lock-ins will be better or bond
forward lock-ins will be better, uh,
will will you go back to deferred
annuity in a different format, to to to
to to fill back the growth, given given
the economics are in your favor or or in
your or industry favor right now?
So, uh, let me give you a hypothetical.
If the yield curve moves downward, I
will reprice.
Right?
Uh, your second point was around regular
pay annuity. We do have regular pay
annuities and we continue to sell those
as well.
Yes, it's swung a little more towards
single pay,
uh, but, uh, we built our regular pay
annuity business as well and we continue
to sell that.
Uh, understood. Understood. And and,
uh, and two two more questions. What One
question is that, given given it's
almost, uh,
six months closer to six months that the
GST
impact was taken on the protection,
uh, have we started repricing or
industry has started repricing the
individual protection business,
uh, to to uh, to to to the extent of
input credit not available or or we
still are on the old pricing nature
only? And and and and related to that is
that, given given we had a very strong
third quarter, now fourth quarter growth
is still there, but but it is, uh,
toning down a bit. So, so so the the the
impact of GST which was there in third
quarter, is it fair to say that now now
it is coming back to normal demand?
We uh,
Sanket, you saw the 60% growth in retail
protection in the quarter.
Right? So, I think
what we have been doing is working at
this granular to one make sure that
protection growth continues.
Uh,
in terms of your question on how we
would look at pricing and have people
taken,
uh, step changes, I believe by and large
the industry has not taken step changes.
You might have one or two players have
taken some minor increases in, uh,
prices, on mass price changes, that too
again, uh, to a degree of 1 to 3% across
the board. Most We have stayed away
from, uh, doing on mass price changes.
We have taken cohorts and worked at
those cohorts where we need to make
updates to pricing. That has been our,
uh, perspective how we could, uh, manage
this entire transition of GST. And you
have seen the, uh, numbers come through
in terms of 60% growth.
I think I made a mistake. I saw a wrong
number. My bad. Actually, I saw only
total protection growth numbers so my
bad. A 60 is a very good number. Yeah.
Lastly, then then then if you're okay to
give the mix of ULIP which has
higher sum assured. And and lastly, just
to confirm that again,
when in your PPT you gave persistency 13
month persistency product writer is
linked non-linked. And lastly, the
non-linked part fell from 86.8 to 73.2.
So so I'm assuming this is predominantly
due to to the zero surrender deferred
annuity plan.
Yeah, so the non-linked persistency drop
is due to the
annuity plan there.
And we've not called out the split of
the high sum assured ULIP.
Okay, thanks. That's it from my side.
Thanks.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Nidesh Jain from Investec.
Please go ahead.
Thanks for the opportunity.
First question is on EV split. So if I
look at the March 25 EV split between
with and net worth for this
in this presentation is the difference
from the last year presentation. So is
there any change in with and EV method
and net worth methodology?
Yeah, so Nidesh sir, you can refer to
slide 63.
We've called that out and given you a
walk from 22 to 26. The key change is
that the shareholder share of the MTM
that's on the assets and derivatives in
the policy holder fund, that's been
reclassified to with from the NW. That
is absolutely no impact on the EV. It's
just a reclassification within within
within NW.
And this is consistent with how the
market is looking. In with
Yes, the MTM derivatives and assets and
derivatives of the policy holders have
been classified in the with.
Okay.
Sure.
Secondly, if I look at that for the
change.
Second
question is like if I look at agency
business last year Q4 it declined 20%.
This year again we have a decline on a
lower base. So what is exactly happening
in this channel
uh why are we not seeing any growth in
the agency channel specifically?
In a large part due to the higher base
that we had of annuity in the previous
year, that has held the
base that we have to work against.
Again, if you look at from a longer time
frame, we still have fairly decent
growth on agency. But yes, in the
shorter term it has been a bit of a
challenge. But like I mentioned earlier,
we are looking at working gradually at
agency, looking at these micro segments.
Building efficiency within the agency
distribution itself.
And similarly, the direct channel is
also lagging in lagging in terms of
growth.
This year and last year also I think Q4
it was weak.
Yes, that's right. There was a base
effect of the direct as well.
So we have in terms of expansion of
these channels are we planning to add
more agents, open more offices or
also
I understand to understand how are we
trying to let's say deliver growth in
these channels in FY27 and how are we
planning today for that growth?
So as I mentioned earlier, we are
looking at these growth centers on a
data driven platform, especially with
the micro market led branch strategy
that we have. Again, using technology
and analytics as productivity levers.
So we'll continue to work at it
gradually Nidesh and then I'm not
working with the fact that the growth
numbers have not been strong. We'll work
at improving these as we go down
gradually into each of these segments.
So first question is on non-par
business. So since the yield curve has
been quite favorable,
why don't we offer better IRRs to the
customers
than fixed deposits?
Have some cut on margins but deliver
better EV growth. Why we are not doing
that?
See, one of the things Nidesh should
understand is that we get priced off the
G sec.
I think by and large insurers in India
have been quite uh
disciplined in their approach to
actually work off the G sec
which may not have been the case in
geographies outside of India.
Um
The pricing of deposits does not really
follow the G sec
threshold.
Um so to that extent at certain points
in time when deposit gets priced
extremely well
relative to non-par products which are
anyway built from a longer term
perspective, customers can swing from
one to another.
So if you were to actually start to cut
margins to be able to deliver on growth
on non-par,
it may not be
accretive to shareholders.
The whole perspective that we carry
Nidesh is that again, look at absolute
VNB. It's not a question of trying to
push one particular product versus
another.
It's to identify what are these
opportunities that exist at this point.
And you're right in the sense that the
non-par offers you a great opportunity
in sense that the yield curve is great.
It's It's uh
steep and is able to give you a good
IRR.
But the competition that also comes
about at least from a sticker price
comparison is FDs which are still
running a fairly steep rate.
So to that extent the non-par does get
subdued.
So and lastly, you can share the
breakup of group protection between term
protection and group term and credit
life.
Yeah, that's in part of our Yeah, that's
in part of our annexures of this pack.
Sure.
That's on slide 56. Yeah. 56. Okay, I
will take it from there.
Thank you, Deven. Thank you.
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Eswar
Ga from Shan Fell Strategic Advisors.
Please [clears throat] go ahead.
Am I audible?
Yes, please go ahead.
>> Yes.
Yeah. Yeah. Thanks so much for the
opportunity.
Just want to ask
a couple of questions.
>> I'm sorry to interrupt. Sir, can you use
your handset mode, please?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm not audible?
Yes, there's slight disturbance. Not
audible? Yeah, go ahead. Go ahead,
please.
Yeah, on slide 64,
the EV walk.
Just want to understand under the
persistency and other variances of 2.6
billion.
How much is pertinent to VNB written in
FY26?
Sorry, can you repeat the question
again?
Yeah, so we have a 2.6 billion
persistency and other variances in the
EV walk,
I just want to understand how much of
that is
due attributed to
VNB written in FY26.
Almost none, Ga.
This is for the past book.
Yeah. Yeah.
Got it.
Got it. I understand. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Manas
Agrawal from Bernstein. Please go ahead.
Hi. My question relates to potential
regulations on commissions. A, do we
have any understanding of what is
happening and when is it expected to
happen? And B, if there are like various
levels of cuts to commissions, how would
your margins and your growth assumptions
change?
Manas, we are not aware of discussions.
We do
we do acknowledge that the regulator has
asked for data which we have provided.
But we have not heard anything beyond
that.
Okay. And second question is let's say
the regulator does something. Um
what would be the sensitivity to growth
and margins on that front?
Um I don't know what the regulator is
thinking on that at this front. So it'll
be a little difficult to comment.
Understood. Thank you.
Thank you.
We'll take our next question from the
line of Shobhit Sharma from HDFC
Securities. Please go ahead.
Yeah, hi sir. Thank you for the
opportunity. I have a question for Anoop
sir. Anoop sir, if I look at our retail
business growth over last 2 3 years have
not been that strong. If you can help us
understand what are the key challenges
which is impacting our growth. Does our
cost optimization initiative which we
have taken over the last 2 3 years are
impacting our growth trajectory? And
given market remains like this for the
entire year and as we remain ULIP
focused, how do you internally plan
growth and do you think we can grow in
line with the private players? And
secondly, we have been very very very we
have a very granular distribution and
agency plays a very important role. The
share of agency channel has been coming
down for the last 2 years if you look
at. So is it because we have seen larger
agents moving to the competition or is
there or there are any other challenges
which are impacting the growth of this
channel?
So I think from a growth perspective, I
think it might be useful to look at
slightly longer period and do a CAGR of
growth and take volatility and base
effects into consideration. I don't
think that cost optimization comes in
the way of growth at all.
In fact, in our industry, I would say
that since we run largely two kinds of
businesses, one is protection led
businesses which are risk based
businesses completely.
And second is savings oriented business
which essentially either get priced off
the equity return or get priced off G
sec.
In both cases, what we then give to the
customer is less the margins
and less
the commission cost.
So, with that in context, I think like
in all asset management businesses,
one has to keep working on cost
structures
both on your fixed cost
as well as optimizing on the commission
cost and distribution cost.
At least in areas where it is not adding
value, but it is giving top line.
So, there were always pockets in large
distributions
where you will see that there are larger
payouts and it is not giving
commensurate
margins or commensurate profits or
profit pools. So, that is a constant
area of optimization that one has to do.
And then on the protection side, one has
to be focused on the risk, which is
early clearance and and make sure that
your underwriting is proper
and your pricing is better.
So, I don't think there is anything sort
of, you know, coming in the way of
growth. We have to go more granular and
you have to get that growth. There are
base effects and which is I'm saying and
like we didn't earlier said, if you look
at, you know, 2 years, 3 years
CAGR,
even if you look at 2 years CAGR, we are
slightly behind, but we do have to catch
up. I understand the sentiment in the
group
that we have to do more growth, but our
focus like we have always said is
absolute VNB.
And in absolute VNB, there are other
levers in addition to the AP. AP is a
very important lever, not to say that it
is not, but there are other levers also
which needs to be flexed
to get the VNB and make the whole
business model more robust.
So, there is nothing sort of, you know,
at this point of time we don't think
cost optimization
or things like that comes in the way of
growth at all.
And secondly, sir, on the agency
channel, how we plan to revive that
channel?
The agency channel, we have had some
large base effects
you know, 2 years back and if you look
at CAGR of few years, it is running at
12-13%.
And as the base effect goes, I think it
will come back and we are also certainly
looking at micro market led
agency. So, hopefully it will come back
sooner than
than we think.
Okay, sir. Thank you and all the best.
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of Ritika
Dua from Bandhan AMC. Please go ahead.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
Two questions were on the
question
I think the ratio Sorry, Ritika, your
voice is sounding muffled. Can you use
your handset mode, please?
Hello.
Can you repeat the question?
Yeah, I'm just saying that sir, that's
questions. One that on the previous the
ratio question on the reclassification
on the EV side. So, while you didn't you
clarified that it doesn't have a
impact on the EV, but just a could you
just explain what we have done and the
objective of the same to do it today.
That's one question. And the second
question is that while I know we are
very early days of IFRS, but
just may I
hear your initial thoughts on as to how
the KPIs would be maybe, you know, in a
IFRS world. So, those are the two
questions. Thank you.
Hi, Ritika. IFRS, let's wait until it
gets implemented. As we see forbearance
current year will be on the existing I
gap.
IND-AS will form financial information
which will be
alternate financials.
So, let's wait until that settles
because we'll have to
recreate the OBS and then look at the
quarterly financial as it is being
generated.
Coming to your first question on this
reclassification, this is just alignment
with what we see in the market at.
Nothing more than that. So, total EV
does not change.
It's just alignment and there is no
specific guidance on where this
particular MGM is to sit.
We realize that uh
it's better to align with the way the
market is presenting it so that you have
comparability.
And if you don't mind, Dhiren, could you
just explain the change again? I'll
obviously go through the presentation,
but if you if you don't mind, could you
just explain the change again?
See, this is the mark to market on the
assets and derivatives
of the policy holder funds.
That is the component that has been
reclassified.
>> [laughter]
>> It's just mark to market on the assets
and derivatives.
Sure. Thank Thank you so much. Thank
you.
I'm done. Thank you. Thank
Thank you.
Next question is from the line of
Dipanjan Ghosh from Citi. Please go
ahead.
Hi. Good evening, everyone. So, a few
questions from my side. You know, first
Dhiren, you mentioned uh
on how you really go about looking at
assumption changes and variances
on the persistency and back book. Now,
specifically mentioned that once select
cohort kind of becomes meaningful
becomes meaningful from a size and
scale, that's when, you know,
you know, the
the variability can come out to be a
meaningful number from a EV perspective
in case there are some differences
between assumptions and realities of
life.
Now, on that backdrop, you also
mentioned that, you know, barring the
annuity product also, there are certain
other products and cohorts where you
have witnessed some challenges.
So, I want to get some color on what
this products or cohorts would be and is
it
any particular mass market strategy or
any particular product which is really
driving this? Just wanted to get some
sense of how all these things can shape
up, let's say from the next 2 to 3 years
also. If you know, if your product or
customer strategies kind of were to
remain the same.
The second question was on the banking
channel.
In your opening remarks, you mentioned
that you want to focus on increasing
your counter share.
So, except ICICI Bank, you know, now
that all the
bank of partnerships except ICICI Bank
have kind of increased in vintage,
could you give some quantitative color
on your counter share
or at least the movement in counter
share over the last few years or maybe
this year?
And finally, third question is on the
ULIP side.
It seems that your ULIP margins have
been moving up over the last 2 years due
to the efforts that you have undertaken,
be it in terms of riders or higher sum
assured.
So, how much headroom would you believe
that you have in this category to kind
of further scale up the margin profile?
And just one small data keeping
question, if you used to break up the
unwinding into
reference rate and real world returns,
if you can kind of quantify that number.
Yeah, so then again, that's alignment
with how the market is presenting it.
We are not breaking the unwind up at
this point.
In terms of persistency, see there are
always going to be some products that
are doing better than the expected uh
persistency and some that are doing
worse.
The way that we have seen this evolve is
that there are certain product and
channel cohorts where we need to do some
work where the persistency has not been
in line.
And that is the reason why we said we
will keep continue to watch these and
see how we could keep the how we could
improve these persistencies
in the years going forward. As Anup also
pointed out, uh
we continuously look at our distribution
and seeing what adds value.
Very clearly, if there are cohorts that
are not adding value, then we look to
step away from those cohorts
and
if you're not able to fix them.
So, to that extent, there is a
continuous re-jigging of our
distribution
what customer segments that we want to
onboard through specific distribution
and corrective action get taken along
with our distribution teams on the
ground.
So, I don't want to call out any
specific channel or any product, but
there are some small cohorts here and
there that we need to fix and that we
continue to work at
in the years as well.
Within the non-ICICI Bank uh we didn't
mention that we've had an increase in
market share by and large. Again, a lot
of the work has gone in across all of
these partnerships to be able to drive
our share.
But again, it
depends upon each particular shop what
our share is in that particular shop.
But by and large, we've been seeing a
positive trend in terms of increasing
share in most places.
Coming to a question on unit linked
and its margin, yes, you're right. Over
the years, we've been able to improve
the margin of our unit linked by
addition of higher sum assured, by
elongating terms.
But I think the way to look at the unit
linked product is
it is a very transparent product. If
you're able to add sufficient protection
to it, it makes it far more meaningful.
It is not a mutual fund product and that
has to be very well understood.
By making sure that you're adding
protection and propositions very
specifically, you're able to cater to
various needs of customers and fulfill
whatever needs that they set out.
So, that's been our approach to product
development and proposition set up for
our customers and we'll continue to keep
working at this
and uncovering newer segments that we
want to expand this into.
All right. Thank you, Dhiren. Just one
small clarification. I mean, in the
persistency question, you mentioned that
you'll be working through this products
and customer cohorts uh
incrementally throughout the year and
going ahead also, right? I mean, is that
the right understanding?
>> That's right. It's It's a continuous
exercise. It's a continuous exercise.
Like as Anup also pointed out, there are
always going to be some segments that
are not up to par.
The point is you try to fix it
because you start with the underlying
proposition that is being provided to
customers
and the sales process. If it doesn't
work, then you stop selling.
Got it.
Thank you and all the best.
Thanks. Thank you.
Next question is from the line of
Nishant Sawant from Kotak. Please go
ahead.
Nishant, your line is unmuted. Please go
ahead with your question.
Yeah, thanks for taking my my question.
You know, just on the protection side
and the the retail the retail term side,
we have seen a lot of tailwinds to this
GST and you know, hopefully you know, we
can see this this continuing as well.
Is this because there is a natural off
take or or as the industry or you
specifically you find that you tailor
certain products or look at certain
segments of
you know, made more investments to grow
the segment?
And in that sense, probably people get
some sense of you know, how long can
this can can this sustain?
Nishant, if the question is
have we created new products and
innovative products? Answer is yes.
We have done that through the year
by providing newer newer propositions
along the way.
But I think one of the biggest tailwinds
that we have got as an industry has been
the GST reform.
And that is felt most in protection in
retail protection because that's where
you see the 18% go up.
So to the customer you're seeing this
improved benefit
come through immediately. In fact, this
is not just for new customers. It's also
available for existing customers because
as they pay the renewal,
the renewals are that much cheaper.
So the way I'm looking at it is that it
has actually helped
create positive word of mouth on retail
protection because very clearly I think
this is one of the essences of our
industry.
Selling protection has to become one of
the core of what this industry does.
In fact, we call it out also in the
audio part of our commentary. Now the
retail sum assured growth for the
industry actually was two and a half
times post the reform than what it was
the pre reform.
So this financial year. So very clearly
I think everyone, it's not just us,
everyone has latched on to this
particular move
and it's up to the industry to make this
a success.
Which it has for the half year that
we've seen.
Got it.
Just now on you know, I I believe
Prudential is setting up a wealth
business. So you know, is there a
partnership or any synergies between
you and between you and and Prudential?
Or is it planned completely separately?
I believe that's a separate company.
So and if if I mean hypothetically if
Prudential wants to move from health to
life, do they need an NOC from you?
Again, these are shareholder matters. I
think we could let's take the
conversation to financial results.
Sure, sure. Those are my questions.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, that was the last
question for today. I would now like to
hand the conference back to Mr. Anup
Bakshi, MD and CEO for closing comments.
Over to you, sir.
Thank you. Thank you very much,
everyone.
Have a good day.
Thank you. On behalf of ICICI Prudential
Life Insurance Company Limited, that
concludes this conference. Thank you for
joining us. Anyone now disconnect your
lines.